[
  {
    "question": "Young's modulus is defined as the ratio of?",
    "optionA": "Volumetric stress and volumetric strain",
    "optionB": "Lateral stress and lateral strain",
    "optionC": "Longitudinal stress and longitudinal strain",
    "optionD": "Shear stress to shear strain",
    "answer": "Longitudinal stress and longitudinal strain"
  },

  {
    "question": "Tensile strength of a material is obtained by dividing the maximum load during the test by the?",
    "optionA": "Area at the time of fracture",
    "optionB": "Original cross-sectional area",
    "optionC": "Average of (A) and (B)",
    "optionD": "Minimum area after fracture",
    "answer": "Original cross-sectional area"
  },

  {
    "question": "If a part is constrained to move and heated, it will develop?",
    "optionA": "Principal stress",
    "optionB": "Tensile stress",
    "optionC": "Compressive stress",
    "optionD": "Shear stress",
    "answer": "Compressive stress"
  },

  {
    "question": "The moment of resistance of a balanced reinforced concrete beam is based on the stresses in?",
    "optionA": "Steel only",
    "optionB": "Concrete only",
    "optionC": "Steel and concrete both",
    "optionD": "None of these",
    "answer": "Steel and concrete both"
  },

  {
    "question": "Which of the following function can the spring perform?",
    "optionA": "Store energy",
    "optionB": "Absorb shock",
    "optionC": "Measure force",
    "optionD": "All of the mentioned",
    "answer": "All of the mentioned"
  },

  {
    "question": "The longest leaf in a leaf spring is called centre leaf?",
    "optionA": "It is called middle leaf",
    "optionB": "It is called master leaf",
    "optionC": "Yes",
    "optionD": "None of the listed",
    "answer": "It is called master leaf"
  },

  {
    "question": "If spring index=2.5, what can be concluded about stresses in the wire?",
    "optionA": "They are high",
    "optionB": "They are negligible",
    "optionC": "They are moderate",
    "optionD": "Cannot be determined",
    "answer": "They are high"
  },

  {
    "question": "The helix angle is very small about 2⁰. The spring is open coiled spring?",
    "optionA": "Yes",
    "optionB": "It is closed coiled spring",
    "optionC": "That small angle isn’t possible",
    "optionD": "None of the listed",
    "answer": "It is closed coiled spring"
  },

  {
    "question": "In an ideal machine, the output as compared to input is?",
    "optionA": "Less",
    "optionB": "More",
    "optionC": "Equal",
    "optionD": "May be less or more depending on efficiency",
    "answer": "Equal"
  },

  {
    "question": "A three rotor systemhas followingnumber of natural frequencies?",
    "optionA": "One",
    "optionB": "Two",
    "optionC": "Three",
    "optionD": "Four",
    "answer": "Two"
  },

  {
    "question": "Which of the following disciplines provides study of the relative motion between the parts of a machine and the forces acting on the parts?",
    "optionA": "Theory of machines",
    "optionB": "Applied mechanics",
    "optionC": "Mechanisms",
    "optionD": "Kinetics",
    "answer": "Theory of machines"
  },

  {
    "question": "Which of the following assumptions are made in torsion theory?",
    "optionA": "Shaft is perfectly straight",
    "optionB": "Material of the shaft is heterogeneous",
    "optionC": "Twist cannot be uniform along the length of the shaft",
    "optionD": "All of the above",
    "answer": "Shaft is perfectly straight"
  },

  {
    "question": "A member subjected to couple produces rotational motion about its longitudinal axis called as?",
    "optionA": "Torsion",
    "optionB": "Twisting moment",
    "optionC": "Both A. and B.",
    "optionD": "None of the above",
    "answer": "Both A. and B."
  },

  {
    "question": "Which of the following relation represents torsional flexibility?",
    "optionA": "GJ",
    "optionB": "GL",
    "optionC": "GJ / L",
    "optionD": "L / GJ",
    "answer": "L / GJ"
  },

  {
    "question": "Stress in the cross section of a shaft at the centre?",
    "optionA": "is zero",
    "optionB": "decreases linearly to the maximum value of at outer surface",
    "optionC": "both a. and b.",
    "optionD": "none of the above",
    "answer": "is zero"
  }
]
